Guide to the John B. Kelly papers AD.MC.058
NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections
- General: Correspondence, Projects, and Collected Materials, 1950-1987
  - Projects: Oman boundaries consultation (Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Sultanate of Oman), 1984-1987
    - Research materials: New Saudi claims, 1980s (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Research materials: Occupation of Hamasa, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Research materials: Oman: developments in the interior, I, 1953 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Research materials: Oman: developments in the interior, II, 1953 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Research materials: PCL exploration / Sultanate authority, 1944-1945 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Research materials: PCL survey of N. Oman, 1937-1939 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Research materials: Revival of the Imamate Rebellion, 1913-1920 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Research materials: The Southern Frontier: Hadramaut, Dhufar, 1955 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Research materials: 1949 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Research materials: [Buraimi 1952] (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Research materials: published materials (excerpts) (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Research materials: Notes (SBK), 1951 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Research materials: Notes (SBK), 1952 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Research materials: Notes, Buraimi (SBK), 1952 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Research materials: Notes: Anglo-American relations-Saudi Arabia (SBK?), 1939-1945 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Research materials: Notes: miscelleneous, surplus (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Research materials: Oman--Miscellaneous, 1919-1939 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Research materials: Thesiger, Wilfred (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Writings, manuscript drafts: "Historical Background" (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Writings, manuscript drafts: "Oman: Oil Exploration and the Limits of Al Bu Said..." (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Writings, manuscript drafts: "Oman: the position created by the Blue and Violet Lines" (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Writings, manuscript drafts: "Oman-Saudi activities in the Dhahirah and Trucial Oman" (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Writings, typescript drafts: "Topography and Tribes of Borderlands" (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Writings, typescript drafts: "Oman, Frontier Study 1": chapters titled "Anglo-Turkish Conventions" and "Anglo-Saudi Frontier Negotiations" (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Writings, typescript drafts: "Oman, Frontier Study 1": chapter titled "The expansion of Ibn Saud's frontiers, 1922-1932" (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Writings, typescript drafts: "Oman, Frontier Study 1": chapter titled "The Reopening of the Frontier Question, 1949" (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Writings, typescript drafts: "Oman, Frontier Study 2," pp. 40-83 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Writings, typescript drafts: "Oman, Frontier Study 2," pp 84-135 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Writings, typescript drafts: "Oman, Frontier Study 2," pp. 136-201 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Writings, typescript drafts: "Oman, Frontier Study 2," pp. 202-280 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Writings, typescript drafts: "Chapter II: The Position Created by the Blue and Violet Lines" (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Writings, typescript drafts: Chapter III: Oil Exploration and the Limits of Al Bu Said... (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Writings, typescript drafts: "The Northern Frontier Districts, 1937-1949" (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Writings, typescript drafts: "The Northern Frontier Districts, 1937-1949" (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Writings: Appendix: The Saudi Arabia-Abu Dhabi Boundary (Box 14, Folder 8)
- Publications and writings, 1956-2018
  - Articles, 1956-1993
    - "The Slave Trade in the Indian Ocean and the Red Sea," undated typescript (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - "The Buraimi Oasis Dispute," International Affairs, July 1956 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - "The Persian Claim to Bahrain," International Affairs, January 1957 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - "A Nice Little Agression," New Statesman and Nation, Feb. 23, 1957 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - "The Legal and Historical Basis of the British in the Persian Gulf," unknown publication, circa 1958 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - "Sovereignty and Jurisdiction in Eastern Arabia," International Affairs, January 1958 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - "Sultanate and Imamate in Oman," Chatham House Memoranda, December 1959 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - "The British Position in the Persian Gulf," The World Today, June 1964 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - "Mehmet Ali's Expedition to the Persian Gulf, 1837-1840, part I," Middle Eastern Studies, July 1965 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - "Mehmet Ali's Expedition to the Persian Gulf, 1837-1840, part II," Middle Eastern Studies, October 1965 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - "The Future in Arabia," International Affairs, October 1966 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - "Salisbury, Curzon and the Kuwait Agreement of 1899," in Studies in International History..., 1967 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - "TLS in the Desert," Journal of Imperial and Commonwealth History,", May 1973 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - "Valuable Oil and Worthless Policies," Encounter, June 1979 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - "A Time for Toughness in the Gulf," Sunday Telegraph, Dec. 2, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - "Great Game or Grand Illusion?" Survey, Spring 1980 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - "The Kremlin and the Gulf," Encounter, April 1980 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - "Saudi Censors," New Republic, 05-17-1980 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - "Oil Imperialism," New Republic, 07-26-1980 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - "The Oil Cringe of the West," Quadrant, July 1980 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - "War Against the West," New Republic, 10-11-1980 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - "Yamani's Book of Revelations," National Review, 7-10-1981 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - "Point/Counterpoint: Security Considerations in the Persian Gulf" (with Hermann Eilts), International Affairs, Spring 1981 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - "The Arming of Saudi Arabia," Wall Street Journal, 10-21-1981 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - "The Arming of Saudi Arabia," in Congressional Record, S12822-S12827, introduced by Sen. Henry Jackson, Nov. 3, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - "Reconsideration: A Saga of the Sands" [about Wilfred Thesiger], New Republic, 01-07-1985 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - "Tremble No Longer Before the Sheikhs," The Times (London), 10-31-1986 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - "Families at War," The Spectator, 11 August 1990 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - "Inexpert Experts: the FO got the Gulf wrong," The Spectator, August 15, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - "Will We Stop Hussein?" National Review, September 3, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - "Like a Wolf in the Fold," National Review, 09-03-1990 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - "Let's Talk Turkey," National Review, September 17, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - "America, the Gulf, and the West," National Review, October 15, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - "L'apres-Saddam Hussein," Politique Internationale, Autumn 1990 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - "Let's Not Leave It to the Arabs," The Spectator, 03-16-1991 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - "Running into the Sand," National Review, 04-01-1991 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - "Can America Bring Peace? A Symposium," National Review, 08-26-1991 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - "Arabian Frontiers and Anglo-American Relations," Shapiro Lecture at London School of Economics, 1991, subsequently published in Government and Opposition, Summer 1992 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - "The Last Crusade?", National Review, 08-23-1993 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Untitled typescript of article about U.S. and U.K. policy toward Iraq, for Sunday Telegraph, February 1998 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Various, Sunday Telegraph, 1980-1991, and undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Various, undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Book reviews, 1962-1998
    - "La question des Iles Bahrein," Middle East Journal, Autumn 1962 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - "Britain's Imperial Role in the Red Sea Area...", Victorian Studies, June 1963 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - "The Persian Gulf in the Twentieth Century," Middle Eastern Affairs, October 1963 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - "The Kurds and Kurdistan...", International Affairs, undated, circa 1964 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - "The Economic Development of Kuwait," International Affairs, January 1966 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - "The View from Steamer Point...", Middle Eastern Studies, January 1966 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - "Facets of Arab Nationalism....", International Affairs, April 1966 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - "The United States and the Arab World," International Affairs, July 1966 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - "Saudi Arabia in the Nineteenth Century," Middle Eastern Studies, October 1966 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - "Britain in the Persian Gulf, 1894-1914" (Busch), Journal of Modern History, June 1970 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - "A South Arabian episode...", Middle Eastern Studies, January 1971 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - "Middle East Record...", Middle Eastern Studies, January 1973 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - "Recollections and reflections of a British diplomat" (Trevelyan), Middle Eastern Studies, October 1973 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - "Nationalism in Asia.." (Kedourie), Journal of Imperial and Commonwealth History, May 1974 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - "Political Dynamics in the Middle East" (Hammond), Survival, Sept./Oct. 1974 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - "Britain, India and the Turkish Empire," SOAS Bulletin, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - "Arabia Without Sultans" (Halliday), Times Higher Education Supplement, January 3, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - "Arabic Political Memoirs and Other Studies" (Kedourie), International Affairs, April 1975 (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - "Revolutionary Transformation in the Arab World (Kazziha), Times Higher Education Supplement, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - "In the Anglo-Arab Labyrinth" (Kedourie), Sunday Telegraph, Jan. 22, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - "The Arabs" (Mansfield), Sunday Telegraph, November 1976 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - "T.E. Lawrence," by Desmond Stewart: review and exchange of correspondence with author, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - "Philby of Arabia" (E. Monroe), Middle Eastern Review, January 1977 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - "Death of a Country: the Civil War in Lebanon" (Balloch), Sunday Telegraph, May 1, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - "The First Kuwait Oil Concession Agreement" (Chisholm), International Affairs, October 1977 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence generated by B. Smith's review of "Militant Islam" (Jansen), The Economist, 1979-1980 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - "Militant Islam," by G.H. Jansen, in The New Republic, p. 27-29, Jan. 26, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - "Militant Islam" (Jansen), New Republic, Jan. 26, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - "House of Saud" (Holden), "Saudi Arabia in the 1980s" (Quandt), New Republic, 05-02-1982 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - "Among the Believers" (Naipaul), Commentary, January 1982 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - "The Kingdom" (Lacey), Commentary, May 1982 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - "Muslim Discovery of Europe (B. Lewis), Commentary, March 1983 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - "The Merchants", "American House of Saud" (S. Emerson), Los Angeles Times, 05-19-1985 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - "T.E. Lawrence: The Selected Letters" (Brown), Washington Times, 05-26-1989 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - "The Islamic Threat," (J. Esposito), Sunday Telegraph, February 1993 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - "The Closed Circle" (Pryce-Jones), Los Angeles Times, 6-18-1989 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - "Imperial Masquerade" (review of book by Edward Said), National Review, 4-26-1993 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - "Islam and the West" (B. Lewis), National Review, 8-26-1993 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - "Bosnia, A Short History (Malcolm), National Review, 05-29-1995 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - "The Middle East: A Brief History" (B. Lewis), National Review, 10-28-1996 (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - "Kosovo: A Short History" (Malcolm), National Review, 07-20-1998 (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - "This Year in Jerusalem" (M. Richler), "Mecca" (Peters), typescript submitted to National Review, undated (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - "Migrations and Cultures" (T. Sowell), unpublished, circa 1996 (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - general, undated (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - general, 1966-1972 (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - International Affairs, 1966-1967 (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - English Historical Review, 1980-1998 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Various, Middle Eastern Studies, 1975-1976 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Various, Sunday Telegraph, 1978-1993 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Various, Times Literary Supplement, 1975-1977 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Various, Time Higher Education Supplement, 1975-1978 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Reprints from other scholars: Kedourie, Elie (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Reprints from other scholars: Kostiner, Joseph (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Reprints from other scholars: various (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Books, 1961-2018 and undated
    - Eastern Arabian Frontiers (1964), typescript draft with edits: preface and introduction (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Eastern Arabian Frontiers (1964), typescript draft with edits: Chapter 1 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Eastern Arabian Frontiers (1964), typescript draft with edits: Chapter 2 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Eastern Arabian Frontiers (1964), typescript draft with edits: Chapter 3 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Eastern Arabian Frontiers (1964), typescript draft with edits: Chapter 4 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Eastern Arabian Frontiers (1964), typescript draft with edits: Chapter 5 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Eastern Arabian Frontiers (1964), typescript draft with edits: Chapter 6 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Eastern Arabian Frontiers (1964), typescript draft with edits: Chapter 7 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Eastern Arabian Frontiers (1964), typescript draft with edits: Conclusion7 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Eastern Arabia (1961) (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Eastern Arabian Frontiers: galley proofs (oversize) (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf: correspondence: Bullard, Sir Reader, 1965-1968 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf: correspondence: Chatham House, 1968-1969 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf: correspondence: General, 1968-1969 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf: correspondence: Publishers, 1965-1969 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf: reviews, 1968-1969 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): galley proofs (1) (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): galley proofs (2) (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): galley proofs (3) (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): galley proofs (4) (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Abysinnia (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Aden / Red Sea (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Affairs of Bushire and the Persian Coast, 1813-1853 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Archival series consulted (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Bahrain, 1783-1840 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Bahrain, 1840-1853 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Bahrain, 1853-1873 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Biography and geography (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: British bases in the Persian Gulf (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: British relations with Persia (1) (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: British relations with Persia (2) (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: British relations with Persia (3) (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Crisis with Persia (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Dispute with Persia...Qishm and Bahrain (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: East India Company, administration and correspondence (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Egypt and the routes to India (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Expedition against the Pirate Coast (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Expedition against the Qawasim (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Foreign Office, India Board (1) (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Foreign Office, India Board (2) (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: India Office Records (1) (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: India Office Records (2) (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: International relations (1) (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: International relations (2) (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: International relations; France in the East to 1813 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Islam (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Kuwait (1) (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Kuwait (2) (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Miscellaneous (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Muscat and Oman (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Muscat and Zanzibar (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Navigation and surveys (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Oman, political history to 1820 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Oman, political history, 1820-1840 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Oman, political history, 1840-1856 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Oman, political history, 1853-1866 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Oman, political history, 1867-1870 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Oman, political history, 1871-1880 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Persia, Foreign Office correspondence, 1841-1847 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Persia, Foreign Office correspondence, 1848-1851 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Persia, Foreign Office correspondence, 1852-1856 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Persian Gulf Residency (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Piracy prior to 1809 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Piracy and the Gulf; Consolidation of maritime peace, 1820-1835 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Piracy in the Gulf (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Qawasim piracy (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Routes to India, the Euphrates Expedition (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Salisbury, Curzon, and the Kuwait Agreement (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Slave trade, 1806-1840 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Trade (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Trucial Oman prior to 1820 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Trucial Oman, 1820-1840 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Trucial Oman, 1840-1853 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Trucial Oman, 1853-1873 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Turkish Arabia (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Turkish expansion (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: Turkish jurisdiction, Bahrain (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: the Wahhabis, to 1820 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: the Wahhabis, 1820-1840 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: the Wahhabis, 1840-1853 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: the Wahhabis, 1853-1873 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Britain and the Persian Gulf (1968): notes: published sources (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Arabia, the Gulf, and the West (1980): galley proof of text (Box OS 1)
    - Arabia, the Gulf, and the West (1980): typescript draft, table of contents and preface (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Arabia, the Gulf, and the West (1980): typescript draft, chapter 1: The Abandonment of Aden (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Arabia, the Gulf, and the West (1980): typescript draft, chapter 2: The Retreat from the Gulf (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Arabia, the Gulf, and the West: typescript draft, chapter 3: Tribal Rebellion, Marxist Revolution (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Arabia, the Gulf, and the West: typescript draft, chapter 4: Sorcerers' Apprentices (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Arabia, the Gulf, and the West: typescript draft, chapter 5: Araby the Blest (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Arabia, the Gulf, and the West: typescript draft, chapter 6: Mene, mene, tekel, uparshin (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Arabia, the Gulf, and the West: typescript draft, chapter 7: The Masquerade (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Arabia, the Gulf, and the West: typescript draft, chapter 8: The 'Sting' (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Arabia, the Gulf, and the West: typescript draft, chapter 9: Gazelles and Lions (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Arabia, the Gulf, and the West: typescript draft, appendix: the Saudi Arabia-Abu Dhabi Frontier (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Desert Dispute (2018)--typescript draft (1): Chapter 1: the Anglo-Turkish Conventions of 1913-1914 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Desert Dispute (2018)--typescript draft (1): Chapter 2: The Spoils of War, 1914-1932 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Desert Dispute (2018)--manuscript draft, Ch. 1: the Anglo-Turkish Conventions of 1913-1914, mss. draft (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Desert Dispute (2018)--manuscript draft, Ch. 1: notes and sources (re: Shakespear mission) (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Desert Dispute (2018)--manuscript draft, Ch. 2: (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Desert Dispute: manuscript draft, chapter 3, notes (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Desert Dispute: manuscript draft, chapter 3, first half (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Desert Dispute: manuscript draft, chapter 3, first half (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Desert Dispute: manuscript draft, chapter 4 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Desert Dispute: manuscript draft, chapter 5 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Desert Dispute: manuscript draft, chapter 6 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Desert Dispute: manuscript draft, chapter 7 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Desert Dispute: manuscript draft, fragments (related to Qatar) (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Desert Dispute: manuscript draft, note cards (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Desert Dispute, Saul B. Kelly typescript: Introduction (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Desert Dispute, Saul B. Kelly typescript: Chapter 1: Anglo-Turkish Convention (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Desert Dispute, Saul B. Kelly typescript: Chapter 2: Spoils of War (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Desert Dispute, Saul B. Kelly typescript: Chapter 3: Oil Concessions and Claims... (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Desert Dispute: unidentified source material, linked to previous folder (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Desert Dispute, Saul B. Kelly typescript: Chapter 4: (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Desert Dispute, Saul B. Kelly typescript: Chapter 5: ARAMCO and the Re-Opening of the Frontier Question (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Desert Dispute, Saul B. Kelly typescript: Chapter 6: The Saudi Incursion to Buraimi (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Desert Dispute, Saul B. Kelly typescript: Chapter 7: The Arbitration Agreement (Box 29, Folder 10)